Harvard University. Corporation. Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835: an inventory
Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835
- II. Pequot land, 1652-1674, .07 cubic feet (7 folders)
  - Manuscript copies of court decisions related to allocation of lands bordering the Pawcatuck River and Mystic River to Harvard College and Thomas Danforth, March 23, 1657/8-May 26, 1658 (2 copies), UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 2
  - Decision of Commissioners from Plymouth and New Haven colonies regarding disputes over Pequot land between Massachusetts and Connecticut colonies, Sept. 16, 1658, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 3
    The commissioners from Plymouth were Thomas Prince and Josiah Winslow; the commissioners from New Haven were Francis Newman and William Leete. They decided that the Mystic River should be the dividing line between Massachusetts- and Connecticut-owned lands (and the colonies' respective rights to allocate them).
  - Manuscript copy of General Court’s description of two hundred fifty acres of Pequot land granted to George Dennison, June 10, 1661, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 4
    The land had been granted to Dennison on Aug. 16, 1660; this decision describes the specifics of the lot, as it was “laid out.” The land appears to have been near Weekapaug.
  - Manuscript copy of General Court’s decision to fine Tobias Sanders and Robert Burdet for trespassing on land in “Souther Towne” (Pawcatuck), May 7, 1662, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 5
    Tobias Sanders and Robert Burdet were brought from Rhode Island and imprisoned in Boston until their trial was held. “Souther Towne” was later called Stonington, and determined to be part of Connecticut.
  - Manuscript copy of a letter from the General Court to (the commissioners of?) Connecticut about land disputes, Oct. 24, 1673, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 6
  - Manuscript extract from records of Court of Election held at Hartford regarding Pawcatuck lands formerly granted to Harvard College, May 14, 1674, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 7
    Document is annotated at the bottom with extract from Dec. 11, 1674 entry in College book, which authorized a survey of “ye College Farm near Pacatuck River in ye Colony of Connecticut.”
- III. Webb Estate (Boston), 1660-1827, .36 cubic feet (53 legal folders and 4 oversize folders)
  In 1660, a highly successful Boston merchant named Henry Webb bequeathed to Harvard College a dwelling house and land in Boston, then rented at £13 per year, as well as a legacy of £50, the income and interest "to be improved either for the maintenance of some poor scholar, or otherwise for the best good of the College." The house and land extended from Cornhill, now part of Washington Street, to Devonshire Street, and the property was among the most profitable of the College real estate holdings because of its central location. For many years, beginning in 1831, the estate was rented to the publishers Little, Brown Co.
  "The Webb Estate." The Historical Magazine and Notes and Queries Concerning the Antiquities, History and Biography of America, August 1860, 246.
  Quincy, Josiah. The History of Harvard University. Cambridge, Mass.: John Owen, 1840.
  This series contains documents related to the Webb Estate, which comprised land, a dwelling house, and spaces for commercial business in Boston. Included are a manuscript copy of Henry Webb's will; leases of the estate, or portions of it, to many individuals; correspondence about the property; memoranda of agreement; documents related to difficulties in procuring rent from tenants; bills and receipts for maintenance work on buildings; and lists of tenants and their rents. Records related to the estate's commercial tenants provide information about small businesses operating in the early nineteenth century in Boston.
  - Manuscript copy of Henry Webb’s will, April 5, 1660, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 8
  - Description of Webb Estate in Boston, June 9, 1709?, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 9
  - Lease of Webb Estate to William Payne for ninety-nine years, April 14, 1710, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 1
    Signed by William Payne, Jer. Allen, and Elizabeth Whitcombe. Verso contains notations of rent payment, 1715-1787
  - Amendment of lease of Webb Estate to William Payne, authorizing Ebenezer Storer to repossess to estate in the case of unpaid rent, March 31, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 10
  - Thomas Fleet and Benjamin Guild’s certification of witnessing Ebenezer Storer demand back rent due on the Webb Estate, April 2, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 11
    The current tenants at the Webb Estate were Gideon Thayer, Francis Thayer, and Jonathan Houghton; they owed six years’ worth of rent, which was £72.
  - Memorandum about tenants who succeeded William Payne at Webb Estate, and recent failures to pay rent, April 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 12
    Memo notes that Ebenezer visited the Webb Estate on April 2, 1789, in the presence of Thomas Fleet and Benjamin Guild, and demanded that the tenants pay their rent.
  - Letter from Edward Gray to Ebenezer Storer about the Webb Estate, April 30, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 13
    Eliza Gray, whose relation to Edward Gray is not specified, was financially involved in the Webb Estate because of an agreement with Gideon Thayer. Thayer had mortgaged his portion of the estate to Eliza, whom he owed money, and in this letter she offered (via Edward) to pay Thayer’s share of the rent.
  - Letter from Russell Sturgis to Ebenezer Storer about Levi Jennings’ tenancy at the Webb Estate, May 4, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 14
    Russell wrote on behalf of his brother, Samuel Sturgis, who wished to procure a lease of the Webb Estate for his friend Levi Jennings, who was living there but could not pay his back rent. Apparently the Sturgises, wealthy traders, were willing to pay it for him.
  - Lease of half of Webb Estate to Elizabeth Gray, May 30, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 15
    Signed by Elizabeth Gray (a widower), Nahum Fay, and Thomas Gray. Lease was for 20 years.
  - Lease of half of Webb Estate to Russell Sturgis and Samuel Sturgis, May 30, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 16
    The Sturgis brothers paid the back rent due (£49) and signed a 20-year lease. Signed by Russell Sturgis, Samuel Sturgis, Edward Jones, and William Dorr.
  - Certification that Elizabeth Gray performed repairs on her portion of the Webb Estate, Nov. 27, 1789, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 17
  - Letter from William Lambert to Ebenezer Storer about rebuilding part of Webb Estate, and proposal to Harvard Corporation about his ideas, April 1798, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 18
  - Letter from J. Brooks Co. to Jonathan Jackson about extending lease of portion of Webb Estate, March 27, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 19
    J. Brooks Co. leased No. 8 Cornhill. Verso reads: “N.B. The firm of J. Brooks Co. is composed of John Brooks, James Hooper, and Daniel B. Nichols.”
  - Letter from John N. Hinkley to Jonathan Jackson about extending lease of portion of Webb Estate, March 27, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 20
    Hinkley leased No. 9 Cornhill.
  - Manuscript copies of letters from Jonathan Jackson to J. Brooks Co. and to John N. Hinkley about extending their leases of the Webb Estate, April 17, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 21
  - Letter from Henry Tolman to Jonathan Jackson about extending lease at Webb Estate, April 29, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 22
    Henry Tolman was tenant of a “painter’s glazier’s shop” on Devonshire Street, part of the Webb Estate.
  - Letter from Margaret Brown to Jonathan Jackson about extending lease at Webb Estate, April 29, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 23
  - Memorandum about rents of Webb Estate, April 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 24
  - Letter from J. Lowell to John Davis about advertising vacancies at Webb Estate, Sept. 8, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 25
  - Conditions of lease of No. 8 Cornhill, on the Webb Estate, to Hervey Nolen, Oct. 1, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 26
    Signed by John Davis and Hervey Nolen.
  - Conditions of lease of a shop on Devonshire Street, on the Webb Estate, Oct. 1, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 27
  - Lease of Webb Estate to Hervey Nolen, Nov. 12, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 9, Folder 1
    Signed by Hervey Nolan and Henry Allen. Annotation notes payment in 1811.
  - Bills from Michael Neef and Barnard Cermenati (for work done on Webb Estate?), Feb. 9, 1811 and March 12, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 28
  - Bernard Cermenati’s agreement to lease house on Devonshire Street, on the Webb Estate, March 14, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 29
  - Memorandum of lease of dwelling house at No. 9 Cornhill, on the Webb Estate, to Caroline H. Fanning, April 22, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 2
    Signed by Caroline H. Fanning and John Davis. Verso contains statement dated April 26, 1811 from Robert Roberts, stating that he agrees to pay the first year’s rent for Fanning, if she should fail to pay.
  - Memorandum regarding interest payable to and receivable from Webb Estate, June 1789-April 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 3
    Verso contains annotations through July 1811.
  - Proposal for insurance of house on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) with Massachusetts Mutual Fire Insurance, July 19, 1811, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 30
  - Memorandum of lease of house and shop on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to John Byrne, July 23, 1813, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 31
    Signed by John Davis, John Byrne, and Henry Ware.
  - Lease of house and shop on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to Ephraim Russell, July 7, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 32
    Signed by Ephraim Russell, John Davis, and John Knapp.
  - List of repairs needed at No. 9 Cornhill (Webb Estate), prepared by Caroline H. Fanning, Aug. 1, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 33
  - Lease of house and shop on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to Joshua Binney, Nov. 1, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 34
    Signed by Joshua Binney, Alexander Nash, John Davis, and John Knapp.
  - Lease of house at No. 9 Cornhill, on the Webb Estate, to Joel Dix, April 22, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 35
    Signed by Joel Dix and Sarah Dix. Indicates payments made from 1815-1818.
  - Manuscript copy of letter from John Davis to Joel Dix about repairs to house at No. 9 Cornhill, May 25, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 36
  - Lease of house on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to Joseph Bourgoin, Nov. 2, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 37
    Bourgoin is described as a “teacher of languages.”
  - Bill from Henry Fowle Son for repairing suction pump at Webb Estate, June 6, 1817, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 38
  - Joel Dix’s receipt from the Town of Boston for taxes paid on Webb Estate, Jan. 13, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 39
  - Lease of house on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to Phineas Dow, Nov. 18, 1818, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 40
    Signed by John Davis, Phineas Dow, J. Savage, and Joseph Newell.
  - William Brown’s agreement to lease the shop on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) for one year, March 6, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 41
  - Manuscript copy of letter from John Davis to Joel Dix requesting his departure from Webb Estate, May 7, 1819, and memoranda about Dix’s account, May 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 42
  - Memorandum about Joel Dix and his occupancy at No. 9 Cornhill (Webb Estate), June 9, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 43
  - Lease of house at No. 9 Cornhill, on the Webb Estate, to Abner Phelps, June 22, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 44
    Signed by John Davis, Abner Phelps, and Lemuel Shaw.
  - Memorandum of agreement to lease store at No. 9½ Cornhill (Webb Estate) to Charles Spring, May 31, 1821, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 45
  - Lease of store at No. 8 Cornhill (Webb Estate) to Isaac Osgood and Charles Spring, Aug. 23, 1821, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 46
    Signed by Isaac Osgood, Charles Spring, John Davis, Jacob Guild, and Charles Winslow.
  - Memorandum of agreement to lease stores on Washington Street (Cornhill / Webb Estate) to William S. Chadwick, 1821, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 47
  - Agreement to extend Deborah Goff’s lease at No. 9 Cornhill (Webb Estate) one year, July 2, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 48
  - Notice about impending repairs to Devonshire Street, Aug. 8, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 49
    Notice is from the “Surveyors of Highways” and is signed by Caleb Hayward, police officer.
  - Memorandum of lease of store at No. 9 Cornhill (Webb Estate) to Edward Shirley Erving, Nov. 2, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 50
    Signed by John Davis, Edward Shirley Erving, Marcia White, and Edward Robbins.
  - Memorandum of lease of store at No. 9 Cornhill (Webb Estate) to Esther Parker, Sept. 16, 1823, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 51
    Signed by John Davis, Esther Parker, and Sarah Plimpton.
  - Lease of store on Washington Street (No. 8 Cornhill / Webb Estate) to Abigail Moulton, April 16, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 52
    Signed by John Davis, Abigail Moulton, Abel Moulton, Edward Holyoke, and William Turner.
  - Lease of shop at No. 16 Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to William Whall, July 21, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 53
    The lease specifies that Whall was “not to boile oil […] or some other combustible” on the property. Signed by William Whall, William Whall, Jr., Eben Tarbell, George W. Godfrey, and P. Dow.
  - Manuscript copy of letter from John Davis to Deborah Goff about new door to be installed at her apartment, Sept. 22, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 54
  - Letter from William S. Chadwick to John Davis about repairs at Webb Estate, Sept. 29, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 55
  - Letter from M.B. Dewey to John Davis about repairs at Webb Estate, Oct. 15, 1825, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 56
  - Letter from assignees of William S. Chadwick (Newhall Eveleth) to John Davis about transfer of Webb Estate lease, April 17, 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 57
    The lease had been transferred to a Mr. Learned.
  - Lease of house and shop on Devonshire Street (Webb Estate) to Archibald McMillan, June 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 58
    Signed by John Davis, Archibald McMillan, John Pear, and John Galbraith.
  - Estimate of rent for Webb Estate from July 1, 1825-July 1, 1826, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 59
  - Account of tenants and rents at Webb Estate from July 1, 1823-Feb. 1, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 60
- IV. Pennoyer Estate, 1670-1829, .26 cubic feet (30 legal folders and 2 oversize folders)
  In his May 1670 will, British merchant William Pennoyer bequeathed £34 per annum from the rent of a 92-acre farm in Norfolk, England to Harvard College, so that "two Fellows and two Scholars [would] forever be educated and brought up in the College called Cambridge in New England, of which I desire one of them so often as occasion shall present, may be of the line of posterity of the said Robert Penoyr, if they be capable of it; and the other of the Colony of Nox, or of late called New Haven colony, if conveniently may be." Although the rental income would fluctuate from year to year and it was not always possible to find descendants of Pennoyer or scholars from New Haven to fund, Pennoyer's bequest provided scholarships for numerous Harvard students for over two centuries. By 1740, the original trustees of Pennoyer's estate had died, and from that year until the farm was sold in 1903 the Governors of Christ's Hospital in England found tenants for the farm, collected rent, and managed the property. A Harvard liaison in England then submitted the appropriate revenues to Harvard. By the late nineteenth century the farm had become unprofitable, largely because of an agricultural depression, and in 1897 the Harvard Corporation decided to sell it. Following several years of administrative challenges, the farm was sold in April 1903 for $4,029.52, which was added to the Pennoyer fund still maintained by Harvard.
  Morison, Samuel Eliot. "The Pennoyer Scholarships." Harvard Alumni Bulletin, March 16, 1934.
  This series contains records related to Pennoyer's bequest to Harvard and includes an extract from his will; legal documents concerning the distribution of his estate; and decades of correspondence with the individuals who took responsibility for transferring the estate rents from the trustees at the Governors of Christ's Hospital to Harvard College. These individuals included Henry Newman, Joseph Mico, Thomas Gibson, and Thomas Gibson, Jr., and their correspondence with the Harvard College Treasurer often includes statements of account and descriptions of purchases made on behalf of the College. Several letters refer to purchases of "philosophical apparatus" (scientific equipment) and books in London, which were then shipped to Massachusetts.
  - Extract from the will of William Pennoyer, 1670, with note from 1773, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 60
    The 1773 note is not part of the will.
  - Passage from an order issued by the Master of the Rolls in London, concerning William Pennoyer’s charitable gifts, March 7, 1706, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 61
    Note on verso: “Received from our benefactor, Mr. Tho[ma]s Hollis of London, March 6, 1727. [Signed] Benjamin Colman.”
  - Legal decisions concerning distribution of Pennoyer estate, and schedules of payments to beneficiaries, July 25, 1706 and March 7, 1708, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 62
    William Rogers was the judge who made these decisions. Document contains two charts outlining the distribution of money from the estate to hospitals, schools, relief for the poor, and other charitable causes.
  - Letter from Henry Newman to John White about revenues from the Pennoyer estate, Feb. 11, 1716/7, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 63
    Newman wrote from Middle Temple, London; letter includes this passage: “And tho the late Lord Chancellor Harcourt was pleased to say that he would as soon consent to throwing the money in ye Thames as to remitting it over to he did not know whom in New England to be spent in Eating and Drinking, I wish only that all charitys here were as well managed as what is in your hands.” Document contains a second brief letter, undated and in an unknown hand.
  - Statement of account, Joseph Mico with Harvard College, April 1767-July 1771, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 64
  - Statement of account, Joseph Mico with Harvard College, April 1767-Feb. 1774, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 4
    Statement refers to the purchase of an orrery.
  - Statement of account, Thomas Gibson with Harvard College, July 1774-Jan. 1781, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 5
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer about payments from the Pennoyer Estate, May 1784, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 65
  - Statement of account, Gibson, Johnson Co. with Harvard College, July 1774-May 1784, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 66
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer about financial matters, Feb. 2, 1785, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 67
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer with statement of account, March 23, 1786, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 68
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer with statement of account, Feb. 4, 1788, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 69
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer with statement of account, Aug. 7, 1788, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 70
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer about financial matters, May 31, 1791; June 21, 1791; and July 31, 1792, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 71
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer about financial matters, Dec. 17, 1793 and Aug. 5, 1796, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 72
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer with statement of account, Dec. 30, 1797, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 73
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer about financial matters, April 5, 1798 and Aug. 13, 1799 (with statement of account), UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 74
    Gibson informed Storer on April 5, 1798, that he would need a renewed power of attorney from Harvard in order to continue to collect rents from the hospital trustees, as his previous power had been granted when Massachusetts was a colony and was no longer considered valid.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson to Ebenezer Storer with statements of account, Dec. 26, 1800; June 6, 1804; and Feb. 2, 1805, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 75
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to Ebenezer Storer about his father’s death and financial matters, with statements of account, Oct. 6, 1806 and June 30, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 76
    This correspondence and all that follows is with Thomas Gibson, Jr., who took over his father's responsibilities upon his death.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to Jonathan Jackson about financial matters, Dec. 3, 1807 and May 6, 1808 and statement of account, Harvard College with William Samuel Jones, 1797-1805 and receipt from Samuel Jones, June 25, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 77
    The receipt was enclosed with one of the letters.
  - Letter from George Higginson to Jonathan Jackson about Thomas Gibson, Jr., Aug. 23, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 78
    Apparently Jackson had heard rumors that Gibson was of a disreputable character, but Higginson set the record straight, informing him that Gibson was successful in dry goods and well respected.
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to Jonathan Jackson, Aug. 23, 1809, with manuscript copies of statement of account and letter from Gibson to Jackson, March 6, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 79
    The letter from Gibson to Jackson had failed to arrive when it was originally sent.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, including statements of account, Aug. 6, 1811; Dec. 6, 1813; and July 2, 1814, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 80
    Letters refer to shipment of books from London to Massachusetts which were delayed because of war-related trade restrictions.
  - Letter from John Davis to Thomas Gibson, Jr., June 3, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 81
    Letter is about political matters and expenditures on books and philosophical apparatus for Harvard. Davis writes: “The return and [?] of the Man of Blood in France is a painful consideration to all considerate men in our community.” Also refers to Edward Everett, then a new Professor of Greek.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, including statements of account, July 12, 1815 and Aug. 18, 1815, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 82
    July 12 letter refers to purchase of philosophical apparatus for Harvard.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, with statement of account, March 11, 1816, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 83
  - Letter from John Davis to Thomas Gibson, Jr., Nov. 23, 1816, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 84
    Letter is about recent purchases of scientific equipment, which included “Ferguson’s best pyrometer,” “Nicholson’s Gravimeter,” “86 lbs. Mercury” (which Davis asked to be removed from the list, as he had found a supplier elsewhere), a silver spatula, and a “Bran mounted prism.”
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, including statements of account, March 10, 1817; Feb. 19, 1818; and June 24, 1819, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 85
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, with statement of account, Aug. 11, 1821, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 86
  - Letter from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Kirkland, with bill of lading and publisher’s bill, March 25, 1822, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 87
    Books were shipped on the vessel called Rasseles, by the company Jonathan Roose Son; bill of lading is dated Dec. 18, 1821. The publishers were Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme, Brown Green and the books purchased were on the subject of Calculus.
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to John Davis, with statements of account, Aug. 24, 1824 and Dec. 4, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 88
  - Letters from Thomas Gibson, Jr. to Ebenezer Francis, Dec. 3, 1828 and May 5, 1829, UAI 15.750 Box 1, Folder 89
    Both letters refer to the financial situation of “the daughter of the late Count Rumsford.” Francis appears to have been worried about her, but she was reportedly not in dire straits (though not affluent).